<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <paragraph>Greeshma G</paragraph>
    <paragraph>7090645883—    greeshmag275@gmail.com—    LinkedIn—    GitHub</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Profile</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Enthusiastic software developer with expertise in Python, Java, C, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Django, React.js,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Node.js, Next.js, PostgreSQL. Experienced in web development, machine learning, data visualization, and open-source</paragraph>
    <paragraph>contributions, with a strong grasp of algorithms, problem-solving, and database management.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Education</paragraph>
    <paragraph>RNS Institute Of TechnologyChannasandra, Banglore  2022-2026</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science9.4 CGPA</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Viveka Pre-University CollegeKota, Udupi2020-2022</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Pre-University in PCMCs97.6</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Experience</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Open Source ContributorGirlscript Summer Of Code (GSSOC)October - November 2024</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Actively  contributed  to  public  repositories  in  GSSoC  Extended  2024,  enhancing  projects  with  meaningful  code</paragraph>
    <paragraph>improvements.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Collaborated on GitHub to resolve issues, improve documentation, and implement new features.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Earned a certificate of participation and secured a rank of 832, demonstrating consistent engagement.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Full Stack Web Developer InternUnified MentorOctober - November 2024</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Applied technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript,  Python (Flask/Django),  and MySQL, improving backend</paragraph>
    <paragraph>logic and frontend UI.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Built a dynamic quiz platform with features like question navigation, scoring, and result analysis.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Designed a responsive blog platform with user authentication, CRUD operations, and a rich text editor.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Projects</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Real Time Chatroom Application—Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Developed a Django-based chat application with functionalities for creating chat rooms, sending messages, images,</paragraph>
    <paragraph>videos, and emojis for interactive communication.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Integrated login and authentication to ensure a personalized and secure chat experience.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>PDF to XML Converter—React.js, Next.js, Nest.js, PostgreSQL, CSS</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Developed a website allowing users to upload PDFs and convert them to XML format.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Implemented options for downloading and printing the converted files.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Blog Website—HTML, CSS, Javascript</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Built a web application of blog website that allows the users to write and post blogs.  They can also comment on</paragraph>
    <paragraph>and view other blogs.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•It also has login and logout options.  User can view the recent posts.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Heap Sort Visualizer—Streamlit</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Built a web application to visually demonstrate the Heap Sort algorithm with step-by-step animations.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>•Provided interface for understanding heap construction, sorting process, and time complexity.</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Technical Skills</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Languages:Java, Python, C, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Frameworks:Django, React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Nest.js, Streamlit, Flask</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Dev Tools:Git, Google Cloud Platform, VS Code, Eclipse</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Libraries:pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Certifications</paragraph>
    <paragraph>IBMData Science -September 21, 2024</paragraph>
    <paragraph>TechFusion HackathonDept of ISE-2023</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Infosys SpringBoardMERN Stack Developer- April 20, 2025</paragraph>
    <paragraph>Infosys SpringBoardServer Side programming with Node.js for beginners - March 28, 2025</paragraph>
    <paragraph>1</paragraph>
</document>